Guide to the Peter Burton papers circa 1960-2008.
Burton, Peter
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Peter Burton papers, circa 1960-2008.
7758
Peter Burton, 1945-
14 cubic feet
Correspondence, subject files, manuscripts, typescripts, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence with British and U.S. authors, articles on Burton's writing, materials documenting Burton's writing, records of Millivres Books, and Burton's alphbetical reference collection.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Journalist for various periodicals (JEREMY, GAY TIMES, HIM) and editor at gay or gay-friendly publishing companies including Gay Men's Press and Millivres, Peter Burton has been integrally involved in aspects of the gay literary world in Great Britain since the 1960s when an open, uncloseted gay press was becoming possible. Burton met Robin Maugham in 1968 and worked with him on many projects until Maugham's death in 1981. Among Burton's own writing are articles, introductions to new editions of works by J.R. Ackerley and E.F. Benson, his 1977 biography of Rod Stewart, and "Leaving It All Behind," his one-act play inspired by the early life and writings of Christopher Isherwood, which was published in 1989 in "The Freezer counter: stories by gay men." Over his career, Burton helped discover and nurture gay writers, compiled several anthologies, and spoke on gay writing at conferences.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
A significant accumulation of correspondence with British and U.S. authors, including correspondence, manuscripts, and typescripts by Robin Maugham. Also, clippings of Burton's own writing in periodicals; material documenting the creation and production of other writing including "Leaving It All Behind" and "The Killing of Georgie," a screenplay based on a Rod Stewart song; some of Burton's diaries; and files relating to the day-to-day running of Millivres Books. Also included is Burton's alphabetical reference collection of photographs, publicity stills, postcards, clippings, obituaries, and some of his own interviews with literary figures.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Burton, Peter, 1945-; Maugham, Robin, 1916-1981.; Millivres Books.
Subjects:
Gays' writings, American.; Gays' writings, English.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Materials are arranged according to the original folder headings, when present, which are the primary level of access.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Writings
Diaries
Box 1
Manuscripts and Published Writings
Boxes 2-3
Correspondence about and Reviews of Peter Burton's Writing
Box 3
Series II. Publishing Papers
Millivres Books
Boxes 3-4
Gay Times and Gay News
Box 4
Reviews
Box 5
Correspondence With Writers
Boxes 5-6
Series III. Robin Maugham
Personal Papers (Correspondence, Photographs)
Box 6
Literary Estate
Box 7
Manuscripts and Published Writing
Boxes 7, 15
Relatives (Press Cuttings and Correspondence)
Box 7
Diaries of F. H. Maugham
Box 16
Series IV. Personal Reference Collection
Alphabetical by Name
Boxes 8-12, 15
Alphabetical by Subject
Boxes 12-13
Press Cuttings
Box 14
Additional Oversized Materials
Box 15
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Writings
  - Diaries, 1974-1994 (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts and Published Writings
    - Amongst the Aliens: Some Aspects of Gay Life (Extracts) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Neil Bartlett, 1990-2008 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Brighton and Hove Gazette, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Douglas Byng (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Billy Gaff, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Mike Gill, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The Green Bay Tree (Notes and Introduction), 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - John Haylock, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Innocent Victims: The Sinking of the Lusitania (Notes) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Innocent Victims: The Sinking of the Lusitania (Treatment) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - In Touch, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - The Killing of Georgie (Bound Manuscript 1) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - The Killing of Georgie (Bound Manuscript 2) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - The Killing of Georgie (Draft) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Tony Kushner, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Leaving It All Behind, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Leaving It All Behind (Notes and Drafts) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Lifelines: Essays on Gay Writers and Writing, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - W. Somerset Maugham (Outlines), 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
    - The Middle Course (Manuscript) (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Outsiders, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Poems, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - The Prisoners of War, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - The Punter, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Q International (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Razzle (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Shaping Up (Unpublished Manuscript) (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Dusty Springfield: "See All Her Faces", 2001 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Interview With James Sutton in Hollyoaks, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - There's More To Love, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Vale of Tears (Original Manuscript), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
    - Vale of Tears (Reject Pages) (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Denton Welch, 1997-1988 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Glenway Wescott/Jerry Rosco, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Michael Wilcox, 1987-2000 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - The Wild Boys (Treatment) (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Oscar Wilde, 1987-2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Woolaston-Ireland Civil Partnership, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ian Young, 1995-2002 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Drafts (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence about and Reviews of Peter Burton's Writing
    - Amongst the Aliens (Reviews), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Catalyst Press, 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Eric Glass, Ltd., 1976-1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - David Higham Associates, Ltd., 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Leaving It All Behind (General Correspondence), 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Leaving It All Behind (Correspondence--London and Brighton Productions), 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Leaving It All Behind (Press--London and Brighton Productions), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Leaving It All Behind (Rotterdam Production), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Parallel Lives (Correspondence), 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Parallel Lives (Reviews), 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Rod Stewart: A Biography (Agreements), 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Rod Stewart: A Biography (Correspondence), 1975-1980 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Rod Stewart: A Biography (Press), 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Vale of Tears (Contract), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Vale of Tears (Reviews), 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Series II. Publishing Papers
  - Millivres Books
    - Advertising (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - American Press, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Babilonia, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Sebastian Beaumont: The Cruelty of Silence, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Sebastian Beaumont: Heroes Are Hard to Find, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Sebastian Beaumont: Heroes Are Hard to Find (Proofs), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
    - Sebastian Beaumont: On the Edge, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - E. F. Benson (Correspondence with Hermitage Books), 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - E. F. Benson: Colin II (Notes), 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - E. F. Benson: Raven's Brood, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - E. F. Benson: The Inheritor, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - E. F. Benson: David of King's, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Biddles Book Manufacturers, 1993-1999 (Box 3, Folder 33-34)
    - Billings & Sons, Ltd., 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Braithwaite, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Bruno Gmunder Publishing House, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Catalogues, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Richard Cawley, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Do Tongues, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Editions Blanche, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Editions Internationale, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Egales, 1995-2007 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Epsilon Press, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - David Evans: A Cat In the Tulips, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - David Evans: Summer Set, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Hugh Fleetwood, 2002-2008 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Gay Men's Press (Miscellaneous), 1994-2006 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Gay Men's Press (To Be Filed), 2002-2004 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Gay Sunshine Press, 1976-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - M. B. Gill with TVFM, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Halisham Typesetting, 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Peter-Paul Hartnett: Weirdo Magnet, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Illustrators, 1991-1997 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Francis King (Photographs of Launch for "A Domestic Animal"), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Kris Kirk and Richard Smith: A Boy Called Mary, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Theo Kolinos: Potential Art Book (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Paul LeChien: The Tattooed Loverboy and Other Drawings (Correspondence), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Paul LeChien: The Tattooed Loverboy and Other Drawings (Dummy), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Magnus, 1996-2002 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Neil Moss Productions (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Press Lists, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - David Rees: Words and Music, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - David Rees (Literary Estate Contracts), 1976-1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Rowholt, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Lawrence Schimel, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Aiden Shaw: Boundaries, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Aiden Shaw: Brutal, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Aiden Shaw: Shit (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Colin Spencer: Spitting Image (2 Versions) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Stilone, 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Michael Tomkins, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Turnaround, 1991-1997 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Turnaround (Accounts), 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Uitgeverij Contact, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Vrolijk, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Ian Watt, Reed International, NZ, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Martin Wixted: Lucia Supreme (E. F. Benson Pastiche), 1994 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Graeme Woolaston: A Diary of the Teens, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Graeme Woolaston: A Diary of the Teens (Contract) (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Graeme Woolaston: The Biker Below the Downs, 1994-1997 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Graeme Woolaston: The Learning of Paul O'Neill, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Graeme Woolaston: The Learning of Paul O'Neill (Dummy), 1993 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Gay Times and Gay News
    - Gay News (Copy and Notes), 1981 (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
    - Gay Times (Hay Festival), 2004 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Gay Times (Possible Contributors/Ideas) (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Gay Times (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Reviews
    - Sebastian Beaumont: Two, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Sebastian Beaumont: Heroes Are Hard to Find, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Sebastian Beaumont: On the Edge, 1991-1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - David Patrick Beavers: Thresholds, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - David Patrick Beavers: The Jackal Awakens, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - David Patrick Beavers: Jackal in the Dark, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - E. F. Benson: Colin II, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - E. F. Benson: Colin, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - E. F. Benson: Raven's Brood, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - E. F. Benson: The Inheritor, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - E. F. Benson: David of King's, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Ned Cresswell: A Hollywood Conscience, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Jack Dickson: Crossing Jordan, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Jack Dickson: Oddfellows, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - David Evans: A Cat in the Tulips, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - David Evans: Summer Set, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Rodney Garland: The Heart in Exile, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Kris Kirk: A Boy Called Mary, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Paul LeChien: The Tattooed Loverboy and Other Drawings, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Simon Lovat: Disorder and Chaos, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Kenneth Martin: The Tin Islands, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Robin Maugham: Enemy!, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Millivres Books As Company, 1993-1996 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Joseph Mills: Obsessions, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Neil Powell: Unreal City, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - David Rees: Words and Music, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - David Rees: Packing It In, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Aiden Shaw: Boundaries, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
    - Aiden Shaw: Brutal, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Graeme Woolaston: The Biker Below the Downs, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Graeme Woolaston: The Learning of Paul O'Neill, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992-1999 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence With Writers
    - Peter Baker, 1996-2001 (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
    - John S. Barrington, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Jeremy Beadle, 1990-1996 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - David Patrick Beavers, 1994-1997 (Box 5, Folder 38-39)
    - David Patrick Beavers: Jackal in the Dark, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Perry Brass, 2002-2004 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Scott Brown, 2002-2008 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Michael Carson, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Richard Chopping, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Stephen Corbin, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Tom Cullen/Gerald Hamilton, 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Jack Dickson: Crossing Jordan, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Jack Dickson: Tangent, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Jack Dickson: Oddfellows, 1995-1998 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Royston Ellis, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - David Evans: A Hollywood Conscience, 1992-1997 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Rick Ferreira: A Chill To the Sunlight, 1977-1981 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Patrick Gale, 1986-1996 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - John Haylock, 1985-2004 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Philip Hoare, 1992-1997 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Francis King, 1976-2008 (Box 5, Folder 56-58)
    - Kenneth Martin, 1991-1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Robin Maugham, 1970-1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence Regarding Robin Maugham, 1970-1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Jeffrey Meyers, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Joseph Mills, 1992-1998 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Joseph Mills: Mainstream Scot and English Gay Stories, 1996-2004 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Richard James Percy, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Neil Powell, 1991-1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - David Rees, 1983-1992 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - David Rees Literary Estate (Letters from Writers), 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - David Rees Literary Estate (Miscellaneous) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Peter Robins, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Patrick Roscoe, 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Tom Sargant, 1993-1996 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Colin Spencer, 1977-1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Noel Virtue, 1990-2001 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Tom Wakefield, 1984-1996 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Tony Warren, 1991-1994 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Denton Welch, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Michael Wilcox, 1982-1994 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - John Willis, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Stephen Wright, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Literary Correspondence (To Be Filed), 1971-2005 (Box 6, Folder 23-25)
- Series III. Robin Maugham
  - Personal Papers (Correspondence, Photographs)
    - Photographs: Western Desert and Midle East, 1941-1947 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Photographs and Clippings: Robin Maugham, Friends, Family (Box 6, Folder 27-28)
    - Kate Mary Bruce: Family Group (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Peter Burton (Correspondence), 1974-1981 (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
    - Correspondence Regarding Books and Plays, 1954-1972 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence (Miscellaneous Personal), 1937-1962 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Mike Davidson (Correspondence), 1949-1975 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Longmans Green & Co. and Mark Longman (Correspondence), 1961-1971 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - William Somerset Maugham, 1945-1965 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Programmes, 1935-1970 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Colin Spencer (Correspondence), 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, 1965-1978 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Literary Estate
    - Maugham Estate Papers, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Maugham Estate General Correspondence, 1981-1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Robin Maugham Obituaries, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Maugham Introductions, Stories, and Memoirs by Peter Burton, 1975-1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Contracts Regarding Robin Maugham's Diaries, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Patrick Newley, 1980-1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - David Pollard (Dissertation), 1994 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Craig Wallace, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts and Published Writing
    - April Ashley (Notes) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "The Art of Survival" in Books and Bookmen, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Awhile in Darkness (Draft) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Select Bibliography (by Peter Burton) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Burton as Maugham, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - By Special Messenger, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Cynthia (Manuscript), 1935 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - DAN '31 (Draft 1) (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - DAN '31 (Draft 2) (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "Desert Bond" in Chambers's Journal, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Enemy! (Manuscript) (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Enemy! in Plays and Players, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - A Fable (Draft) (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Frightened Gazelle (Draft) (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Gay Sunshine Interview, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - "The Ghost Ship" in Today, Oversize (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - He Must Return (Manuscript) (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - How Are You, Johnnie? (Manuscript) (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Kenneth D. Long: Life Story (Notes and Draft) (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - "The Last Gaugin" in King, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - William Lawrence Interview in Evening Argus Weekend, Oversize (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Review: The Man With Two Shadows, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - The Maugham Diaries in The Sunday Review, Oversize (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Mukhtar and Mabrouka" in Better Living, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Never Again (Draft) (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - The People: "The Monk in Ceylon," "Hong Kong Drugs," and "The Astrologer", 1961-1965 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - A Question of Retreat and The Scarf (Draft and Manuscript) (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - The Refuge (Draft) (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - The Second Window (Notes), 1964 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Send Up (Manuscript) (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - The Servant (BBC Radio 4), 2005 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Play Without Words/The Servant (National Theatre), 2003 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - The Servant (Lyric Theatre, Hammersmith), 2001 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - The Servant (Birmingham Revival), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - The Servant (Connaught Theatre, Worthing), 1958 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Somerset And All the Maughams, 1964-1967 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Tail Buttons (Draft) (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Tribute to Airy Neave in Bootleg, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous Drafts and Notes, 1935-? (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Relatives (Press Cuttings and Correspondence)
    - Maugham Family (Clippings), 1998-2007 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Somerset Maugham and the Maugham Dynasty (Press), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - W. S. Maugham (Clippings, Photos, Calling Card), ?-1993 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - W. S. Maugham (Clippings), 1962-1996 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - W. S. Maugham and Family (Clippings), 1948-1996 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - F. H. Maugham (Correspondence), 1922-1958 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Diaries of F. H. Maugham, 1891-1941 (Box 16)
- Series IV. Personal Reference Collection
  - Alphabetical by Name
    - People "A" (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - John Adams (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Peter Ackroyd (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Afro-Latino (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - AIDS: Various Pamphlets (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Edward Albee (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Pedro Almodorar (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Marc Almond (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Martin Amis (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Anastasia and the Romanovs (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Julie Andrews (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Queen Anne (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - P. P. Arnold (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "The Art of Biography" Interviews in Gay Times (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Peggy Ashcroft (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Associates/Billie MacKenzie (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Christopher Atkins (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - W. H. Auden (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Aurra (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - People "B" (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Lauren Bacall (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Don Bachardy (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Francis Bacon (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Paul Bailey (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Philip (Pickle) Bakal (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Ian David Baker (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - James Robert Baker (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Josephine Baker (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Peter Baker (Unpublished Manuscripts) (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Lucille Ball (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - David Bannerman (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - BAP (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Keith Barker-Main (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Stephen Barlow (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Julian Barnes (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - The Beach Boys (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Jeremy J. Beadle (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - James Beard (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Aubrey Beardsley (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - The Beatles (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Sebastian Beaumont (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Lord Timothy Beaumont (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Patrick Beavers (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Dave Bedford (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Stefan Bednarczyk (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Vanessa Bell (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Pat Benetar (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Jill Bennett (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - E. F. Benson (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Earlene Bentley (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Sandra Bernhard (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Biddie (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Big Town Playboys (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - The Biz (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Bjork (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - David Blaize (Introduction for Hogarth Press) (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Stephen Bleach (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Lucy Jane Bledsoe (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Philip Bliss (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - The Blue Nile (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Blur (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Dirk Bogarde (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Marc Bolan (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Gary U. S. Bonds (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Bon Jovi (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Borders Group (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Kate Bornstein (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Miguel Bose (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - David Bowie (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Paul Bowles (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Al Bowlly (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Bracknell Festival (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Billy Bragg (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Brains (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Christopher Bram (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Marlon Brando (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Lauren Branigan (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Breakfast Band (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Brighton Ourstory Project (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Joanna Briscoe (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Benjamin Britten (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Bronski Beat (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Elkie Brooks (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - Louise Brooks (Box 8, Folder 84)
    - Brigid Brophy (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - Bros (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - Brother Beyond (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Miguel Brown (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - Dora Bryan (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Katherine Bucknell (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - Mark Bunyan (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Raymond Burr (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - William S. Burroughs (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Sir Richard Burton (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - Bushes Murder 1996 (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Lord Byron (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - People "C" (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Cabaret Voltaire (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - Cats (Photographs, Cards, Clippings, Newsletters, Calendars) (Box 8, Folder 99-103)
    - Cats, Oversize (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Simon Callow (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Stan Campbell (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Cantabile (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - Truman Capote (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - Edward Carpenter (Box 8, Folder 108)